Guide to the Extra-illustrated Life of Nollekens
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Pasquin., undated; engraving; 17 x 12.5 cm. (Box 1-353)
  Engravings; Pasquin, Anthony, 1761-1818
- A Macaroni. Printseller. Pub. accor. to Act by M. Darly May 5th 1772, 39 Strand., 1772 May 5; engraving; 5 x 18 cm. (Box 1-353)
  Portrait of Mathias Darly.
  Engravings; Darly, Matthias
- Portrait of Mr. and Mrs. Gibson. A. Walker Sculp. Vol. III p. 64., undated; engraving; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 1-358)
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1822 August 15; Combe, Taylor, 1774-1826; 2 pages; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 1-358)
  Asking him to come next Sunday so that he can sketch in Kew Gardens. Combe was superintendent of coins and medals at the British Museum with Smith was there.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew
- Joseph Planta Esqe. F.R.S. Engraved by W. Sharp from a medallion by Pistrucci., undated; engraving; 18 x 13 cm. (Box 1-360)
  Medallion portrait of Joseph Planta.
  Engravings; Planta, Joseph, 1744-1827
- Letter from Joseph Planta., 1821 October 31; Planta, Joseph, 1744-1827; 1 page; 17.5 x 11 cm. (Box 1-360)
  Admitting Miss Trail, and two guests, to see the prints at the British Museum, upon application to J.T. Smith. Planta was principal librarian at the British Museum from 1799 until his death.
- Noel Desenfans, Esqr. Painted by Northcote. Engraved by Freeman. Published by W. Smith, 23 Lisle Street, Leicester Square., undated; engraving; 12.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 1-361)
  Portrait of Noel Joseph Desenfans.
  Engravings; Desenfans, Noel Joseph, 1745-1807
- J.P. Kemble. Célébre Tragédien Anglais. Né en 1757, mort en 1823. Lith. de Ducarme. Galerie Universelle. Publiée par Blaisot., undated; lithograph; 29 x 21.5 cm. (Box 1-362)
  Portrait of John Phillilp Kemble.
  Lithographs; Kemble, John Phillip, 1757-1823
- George, Earl of Egremont. From an original picture by T. Phillips, Esq.R.A. in his own possession. Drawn by J. Wright, engraved by J.S. Agar. Published April 16, 1810, by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1810 April 16; engraving; 31 x 25.5 cm. (Box 1-363)
  Portrait of George O'Brien Wyndham.
  Engravings; Egremont, George O'Brien Wyndham, Earl of, 1751-1837
- Letter to Mr. Ridgway., 1819 August 9; Essex, George Capel-Coningsby, Earl of, 1757-1839; 1 page; 11 x 11.5 cm. (Box 1-364)
  Asking him to send a pamphlet (largely illegible).
- Signed receipt., 1797 September 8; Pether, Abraham, 1756-1812; 1 page; 8 x 19 cm. (Box 1-365)
  Acknowledging receipt of 16 guineas for two paintings by Pether.
- Samuel Birch Esqr. Lieutenant Colonel Commandant of the First Regiment of Loyal London Volunteers. European Magazine. Engraved by Ridley from an original painting by Drummond. Published by J. Asperne, at the Bible, Gown & Constitution, Cornhill. 1 Novr. 1805., 1805 November 1; engraving; 21 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-371)
  Portrait of Samuel Birch.
  Engravings; Birch, Samuel, 1757-1841
- John Jackson R.A. J. Jackson Esqr. R.A. Pinxt. Thompson, Sculp. Published for the Proprietors of the European Magazine by Lupton Relfe, Corhill, Sepr. 1, 1823., 1823 September 1; engraving; 18 x 14 cm. (Box 1-375)
  Portrait of John Jackson.
  Engravings; Jackson, John, 1778-1831
- Her Royal Highness the Princess of Wales. From a bust by Joseph Nollekens Esqr. RA. Drawn by I. Taylor Esqr. Engraved by T. Blood. For the European Magazine - Published by J. Asperne. 32 Cornhill 1 May 1813., 1813 May 1; engraving; 16.5 x 11 cm. (Box 1-376)
  Portrait of the Charlotte Augusta, Princess of Wales.
  Engravings; Charlotte Augusta, Princess of Great Britain, 1796-1817
- Spencer Percival. From a bust by Joseph Nollekens, R.A. Drawn by J. Taylor. Engraved by T. Blood [caption from a handwritten note], undated; engraving; 16 x 11 cm. (Box 1-379)
  Portrait of a bust of Spencer Perceval.
  Engravings; Perceval, Spencer, 1762-1812
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1809 October 3; Davison, Alexander, 1750-1829; 1 page; 22 x 20 cm. (Box 1-386)
  Apologizing for having kept three (unnamed) volumes so long: he has been much amused by them.
- William Wilberforce Esq. Member of Pariliament for the County of York. Engraved by T. Vendramini, from an original drawing by H. Edridge. Published Oct. 27, 1809 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1809 October 27; engraving; 32 cm. (Box 1-388)
  Portrait of William Wilberforce.
  Engravings; Wilberforce, William, 1759-1833
- John Soane Esqr. Engraved by T. Blood for the European Magazine from an original painting by Drummond A.R.A. London. Published by J. Asperne, Cornhill 1st February 1813., 1813 February 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-392)
  Portrait of Sir John Soane.
  Engravings; Soane, John, Sir, 1753-1837
- Samuel Rogers, Esqr. Engraved by H. Meyer, from a drawing by Sir Thomas Lawrence, P.R.A. Published Augt. 16, 1822 by T. Cadell, Strand, London., 1822 August 16; engraving; 32 x 25 cm. (Box 1-393)
  Portrait of Samuel Rogers.
  Engravings; Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855
- Untitled portrait of Joseph Nollekens., undated; engraving; 13.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-1)
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1815 December 25; Newcastle, Henry Pelham, Duke of, 1811-1864; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 2-1)
  "I will beg of you to send one of the plaster busts to Mr. Rowlands ... I mean it for a New Year's present ... I send you a hamper of game & wish you a happy New Year ..."
- Letter enquiring about "poor Goblet" (i.e. Henry Goblet), Nollekens' studio attendant. Sender's signature is illegible., 1826 April 28; 2 pages; 20 x 12.5 cm. (Box 2-7)
  Correspondence; Goblet, Henry
- Michel Angelo Buonarroti. Painted by himself. Engraved by Cosmo Armstrong. London. Pub. for the Proprietor. December, 1822., 1822 December; engraving; 13 x 6 cm. (Box 2-10)
  Portrait of Michelangelo Buonarroti.
- Earl Spencers St. James's Park., undated; engraving; 6.5 x 10 cm. (Box 2-11)
  View of Spencer House, St. James's Park, London.
  Engravings; Spencer House (London, England)
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1820 February 20; Balme, Edward, 1753 or 4-1822; 1 page; 16.5 x 23 cm. (Box 2-16)
  Mentioning Francis Douce and also the print collection of Martin van Heemskerck, at one time numbering 40,000 but now "dwindled to little more than 100", in the possession of Richard Cosway.
  Correspondence; Heemskerk, Martin van, 1498-1574; Douce, Francis, 1757-1834; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Cosway, Richard, 1740-1821
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1824 January 5; Symmons, Charles, 1749-1826; 2 pages; 20.5 x 16.5 cm. (Box 2-18)
  Regarding Joseph Nollekens' will, asking when legacies will be paid and fulminating against Francis Douce (who was the eventual principal legatee), calling him "that shabby and in fact dishonest fellow, Douce".
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Douce, Francis, 1757-1834
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., undated; Douce, Francis, 1757-1834; 1 page; 19 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-20)
  Arranging to meet "to settle the plan of moving".
- Francis Douce Esqr. C. Prosperi, Fect, 1812., engraving; 17.5 x 14.5 cm. (Box 2-21)
  Engraved reproduction of a bust of Francis Douce.
  Engravings; Douce, Francis, 1757-1834
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1820 February 20; Balme, Edward, 1753 or 4-1822; 1 page; 18.5 x 11 cm. (Box 2-24)
  About a dinner to take place with "our Friend Mr. [Francis] Douce".
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Douce, Francis, 1757-1834
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1824 October 13; Peck, Jasper; 2 pages; 22.5 x 19 cm. (Box 1-32)
  About Nollekens' will: "more persons of the name of Le Rouz are coming forward to endeavour to prove themselves the next of kin to Mr. Nollekens, the possibility therefore exists that both my brother and self may be oblig'd to return every shilling".
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- Untitled portrait of Robert Stewart, Marquess of Londonderry., undated; engraving; 16 x 14 cm. (Box 2-44)
  Engravings; Londonderry, Robert Stewart, Marquess of, 1739-1821
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., undated; Knowles, John, 1781-1841; 1 page; 23 x 18 cm. (Box 2-45)
  Acknowledging receipt of the Smith's Life of Nollekens and enclosing a guinea as payment.
- Miss Mellon, The Present Mrs. Coutts., undated; engraving; 13 x 8 cm. (Box 2-46)
  Portrait of Harriot Beauclerk.
  Engravings; Beauclerk, Harriot, 1777?-1837
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1825 October 17; Henning, John, 1771-1851; 1 page; 20.5 x 13 cm. (Box 2-48)
  Introducing Mr. Banks who is a reader at the Museum. "He is anxious for his son (who follows the art of Drawing and Painting) to study from the antiques in the museum".
- Clipping. "Riding Wiggs"., 1744; 1 page; 4 x 8 cm. (Box 2-48)
  Advertising wigs made and sold by John Bennet, "in the newest fashion and in a more durable manner."
  Clippings; Wigs
- Untitled and unidentified portrait., undated; engraving; 17 x 13 cm. (Box 2-50)
- To the Co-Heirs of Sir John Clobery, this plate is most humbly inscribed. Pag. 45. H. Hilsbergh sculp., undated; engraving; 18 x 10 cm. (Box 2-50)
  Portrait of Sir John Clobery.
  Engravings; Clobery, John, Sir
- Thomas Osborne, Earl of Danby. From an original by Sir Peter Lely ... His autograph from an original letter in the possession of John Thane., undated; engraving; 18.5 x 11 cm. (Box 2-52)
  Portrait of Thomas Osborne, Duke of Leeds.
  Engravings; Leeds, Thomas Osborne, Duke of, 1631-1712
- Taylor as Doodle [from handwritten note]., undated; engraving; 15 x 10 cm. (Box 2-53)
  Unidentified portrait.
  Wigs; Engravings
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1822 December 16; Christie, Mr. (James), 1730-1803; 1 page; 22 x 19 cm. (Box 2-57)
  Concerning the sale of Mr. Balme's property. Also mentions other business: "I shall set off to view an estate in Denbighshire and shall be absent near a fortnight".
- George-O'Brien Wyndham, F.R.S. & F.S.A. Earl of Egremont. Printed by Thos. Phillips, R.A. Engraved by H. Cook. Fisher, Son & Co. London, 1832., engraving; 16 x 10 cm. (Box 2-59)
  Portrait of George O'Brien Wyndham, Earl of Egremont.
- Fragment of an envelope from George O'Brien Wyndham, Earl of Egremont. June 25 1799., 1799 June 25; Egremont, George O'Brien Wyndham, Earl of, 1751-1837; 1 page; 8 x 14 cm. (Box 2-60)
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., undated; Bagot, William, 1773-1856; 1 page; 22.5 x 19 cm. (Box 2-60)
  On his own behalf and that of Mr. Richard Bagot about "properly and safely" packing the busts of Mr. Pitt and arranging their delivery by Wakeman's Waggon. 13 September.
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Bagot, Richard, 1782-1854
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1815 September 4; Liverpool, Robert Banks Jenkinson, Earl of, 1770-1828; 1 page; 16 x 11 cm. (Box 2-60)
  Arranging to meet.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1807 November 6; Plinth, Charles; 1 page; 23 x 19.5 cm. (Box 2-60)
  Inquiring when the busts of Pitt and Fox will be ready and for which the sum of 12 guineas has been arranged. Charles Plinth was a sculpture dealer at Liverpool.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1808 July 17; Camden, John Jeffreys Pratt, Marquis of, 1759-1840; 1 page; 24 x 19 cm. (Box 2-60)
  About paying for the bust of Pitt.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1807 October 22; Brownlow, John Cust, 1st Earl, 1779-1853; 1 page; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-60)
  About the bust of Pitt.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1807 September 11; Brownlow, John Cust, 1st Earl, 1779-1853; 1 page; 25 x 20.5 cm. (Box 2-60)
- Monument Erected to the Memory of Mrs. Howard. J. Nollekins Esqr. R.A. sculptor. Engraved by Heath. London. Published as the act directs. April 1, 1808, for La Belle Assemblee. N. 29 by John Bell, Southampton Street, Strand., 1808 April 1; engraving; 14 x 16.5 cm. (Box 2-60)
  View of Nollekens' sculpture to the memory of Maria Howard, who died in childbirth in 1789.
- William Pitt. Nollekens. Normand fils., undated; engraving; 15 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-61)
  Depiction of a statue of William Pitt by Nollekens, accompanied by text describing the work.
  Engravings; Pitt, William, 1759-1806
- Mrs. Howard's Monument. Nollekens. Normand fils., undated; engraving; 11.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 2-61)
  Depiction of a statue of Mrs. Howard by Nollekens, accompanied by text describing the work.
- George IV. Engraved by W.T. Fry. Copied by permission of Mr. S.W. Reynolds from his original portrait for this work only. Published April 1, 1823, by T. Boys, 7 Ludgate Hill., 1823 April 1; engraving; 13.5 x 8.5 cm. (Box 2-62)
  Portrait of King George IV.
- James Barry Esqr. R.A. Painted by J. Barry. Engraved by W.C. Edwards., undated; engraving; 13 x 10 cm. (Box 2-65)
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1808 January 13; Brownlow, John Cust, 1st Earl, 1779-1853; 1 page; 22 x 18 cm. (Box 2-66)
  Asking for a bust to be made of his father, lately deceased.
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., undated; Russell, W.; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 2-66)
  About pedestals, presumably for busts. He will "leave the Pedestals entirely to your taste - the room in which they are to stand is not very lofty - part of the furniture is gilt, therefore I think a little gold in the letters would have a more appropriate appearance - perhaps it might be mixed with brown...". 10 October.
  Pedestals; Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1826 January 2; DeVille, James; 3 pages; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-66)
  Includes list of busts or reliefs by Nollekens of which he has the moulds, mentioning some sixty names of sitters, also listing six busts by Roubilliac in Nolleken's collection.
  Correspondence; Roubiliac, Louis François, 1702-1762; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Joseph Nollekens Esqr. R.A. Engraved by William Bond from a drawing by John Jackson Esqr. R.A. London, Published by Henry Colburn, New Burlington Street, Octr. 1828., 1828 October; engraving; 22 x 13.5 cm. (Box 2-67)
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1812 June 26; Gregory, Richard; 1 page; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-68)
  About the inscription on the bust of his father and including instructions about sending the bust to Holyhead (from where it would be transported to Ireland and Coole). Richard is presumably the eldest son of Robert Gregory (1729?-1810) East India Company director and politician, of Coole Park. The bust is doubtless of his late father.
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; Gregory, Robert, 1729?-1810
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1826 December 14; Bridge, John, 1755-1834; 1 page; 13.5 x 11 cm. (Box 2-74)
  Sending an impression of a silver porringer. Letter accompanied by signature of J.T. Smith.
- Letter presumably to Joseph Nollekens., 1782; Pelham, Charles; 2 pages; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-76)
  Giving him prior information about a motion due to be voted on by the House of Commons commissioning a monument to be erected in Westminster Abbey in honor of Lord Roberts Manners "who fell in the late engagement in Dominica".
  Correspondence; Manners, Robert, 1758-1782; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Carolina Symmons. Drawn & engraved by M. Haughton from the original marble by J. Nollekens, R.A., undated; engraving; 14.5 x 10 cm. (Box 2-78)
  Engraving of Nollekens's bust of Carolina Symmons (i.e. Caroline Symmons?, young poet 1789-1803).
  Engravings; Symmons, Caroline, 1789-1803
- The Right Honourable George Canning from a bust by J. Nollekens Esqr. R.A., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-80)
  Engraving of Nollekens's bust of George Canning.
  Engravings; Canning, George, 1770-1827
- Joseph Gascoigne Nightingale Esqrs. Monument. O'Neal del. A. Smith sculp., undated; 17.5 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-86)
  View of Roubilliac's monument for Joseph Gascoigne Nightingale in St Michael's chapel, off the north transept of Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Roubiliac, Louis François, 1702-1762; Westminster Abbey; Nightingale, Joseph Gascoigne, 1695-1752
- Three clippings on the sale of Peter Gaspar Scheemakers's sculptures., 1750-1757; 1 page; 2 x 8 cm., 3 x 8 cm., 7.5 x 8 cm. (Box 2-103)
  Clippings accompanied by signature of Scheemaker.
  Clippings; Scheemakers, Peter Gaspar, 1691?-1781
- The Monument of Shakespeare in Westminster Abbey. Engraved by B. Holl., engraving; 21 x 12 cm. (Box 2-104)
  View of Scheemakers's monument of William Shakespeare in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Westminster Abbey; Scheemakers, Peter Gaspar, 1691?-1781; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., undated; Smedley, Henry; 1 page; 18 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-105)
  Asking for two friends of his to see Mr. Payne Knight's Claudes (i.e. works by Claude Lorrain) if the Museum is open.
  Correspondence; Knight, Richard Payne, 1751-1824; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Lorrain, Claude, 1600-1682
- Multiple views of Stowe Gardens. Published ... 1750. B. Seeley delin., 4 pages; 18.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 2-106)
  Views include The Sleeping Parlour, The Witch House, The Temple of Modern Virtue, The Temple of Antient Virtue, The Shell Bridge, The Temple of British Worthies, The Chinese House, The Temple of Contemplation, the Grotto, Deido's Cave, The Rotunda, King George 2, Queen Caroline, The Temple of Friendship, the Pebble Alcove, The Imperial Closet, and Congreve's Monument.
  Stowe Gardens (England); Engravings; Scheemakers, Peter Gaspar, 1691?-1781
- Sir Isace Newton. Kent delin. G.V. Neist sc., undated; engraving; 14 x 8.5 cm. (Box 2-112)
  Engraving of Michael Rysbrack's monument of Sir Isaac Newton, in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Westminster Abbey; Newton, Isaac, 1642-1727; Rysbrack, Michael, 1694-1770
- Letter to John Boydell., undated; Damer, Anne Seymour, 1748 or 9-1828; 1 page; 18 x 11 cm. (Box 2-118)
  Asking him to let Mr. (Francis) Legat know that she wishes to speak with him. 19 June, no year.
  Correspondence; Legat, Francis, 1755-1809; Boydell, John, 1720-1804
- Envelope fragment addressed to A.B. Lambert Esq.?, 1816 August 17; 1 page; 7 x 12.5 cm. (Box 2-125)
- Sir Abraham Hume, Bart. F.R.S. S.A. Painted by H. Edridge. Engraved by J. Jenkins. Fisher, Son & Co. London, 1836., engraving; 17 x 10 cm. (Box 2-126)
  Related Materials
  Portrait of Sir Abraham Hume.
  Engravings; Hume, Sir Abraham, 1749-1838
- James Northcote Esq. R.A. in his 82nd year. Engraved by T. Wright after a drawing by A. Wivell., undated; engraving; 17 x 14 cm. (Box 2-126)
- Frederic Earl of Carlisle. Romney Pinxt. T. Holloway sculpt., undated; engraving; 17 x 11 cm. (Box 2-140)
  Portrait of Frederick Howard, Earl of Carlisle.
  Engravings; Carlisle, Frederick Howard, Earl of, 1748-1825
- The North East View of Camberwel Church. Chatelain delin. J. Roberts sculp., undated; engraving; 8.5 x 13.5 cm. (Box 2-144)
  View of the Camberwell Church.
- John Jackson, R.A. W.C. Edwards., undated; engraving; 17 x 12 cm. (Box 2-146)
- Dr. Hinchcliffe, Bishop of Peterborough. Drawn from life by W.H. Brown, engraved by W. Grainger and published according to Act of Parliament, by C. Cooke, No. 17 Paternoster row. July 7th 1791., 1791 July 7; engraving; 11 x 9 cm. (Box 2-150)
  Portrait of John Hinchcliffe.
  Engravings; Hinchcliffe, John, 1731-1794
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., Hinchcliffe, John, 1731-1794; 1 page; 20.5 x 15 cm. (Box 2-151)
  Asking Smith to give his son a lesson.
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1824 March 4; Bridge, John, 1755-1834; 1 page; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-152)
  Concerning the value of a portrait of Clarissa Hayward by Ozias Humphry.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810
- The Entrance to Coade and Sealy's Gallery of Sculpture of Artificial Stone, Westminster Bridge. Drawn and engraved by S. Rawle. Published by J. Sewell Cornhill. Feb. 1, 1802., 1802 February 1; engraving; 19 x 12 cm. (Box 2-155)
  View of Coade and Sealy's Gallery of Sculpture.
  Coade stone; Engravings; Coade and Sealy (Firm)
- Monument of the Earl of Chatham, in Westminster Abbey., undated; engraving; 17.5 x 11 cm. (Box 2-156)
  Engraving of John Bacon's monument of William Pitt the Younger, in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Bacon, John, 1740-1799; Pitt, William, 1759-1806; Westminster Abbey
- Lord Chatham's Monument now erecting in Guild-hall at the expence of the City of London., undated; engraving; 17 x 11 cm. (Box 2-157)
  Engraving of John Bacon's monument of William Pitt the Elder, in Guildhall.
  Engravings; Guildhall (London, England); Bacon, John, 1740-1799; Pitt, William, Earl of Chatham, 1708-1778
- To the Memory of Nicholas Rowe, Esq. M. Rysbrake fecit., undated; engraving; 20 x 11 cm. (Box 2-159)
  View of John Michael Rysbrack's monument to Nicholas Rowe, in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Rysbrack, Michael, 1694-1770; Westminster Abbey; Rowe, Nicholas, 1674-1718
- Dr. Johnson's Monument in St. Paul's Church. J. Bacon Statuary, J. Basire sculp. Publish'd by J. Sewell Cornhill April 1, 1796., 1796 april 1; engraving; 20 x 12 cm. (Box 2-158)
  View of John Bacon's Monument to Dr. Samuel Johnson, in St. Paul's Cathedral.
  Engravings; Bacon, John, 1740-1799; St. Paul's Cathedral (London, England); Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784
- Ant. Canova. John Jackson Esqr. R.A. pinxt. Thomson sculp., undated; engraving; 18 x 12.5 cm. (Box 2-161)
  Portrait of Antonio Canova.
- A Plan & Elevation of the New Bridge now building over the River Thames near Somerset Place in the Strand. No. 11 of Ackermann's Repository of Arts & Pub. 1 Novr. 1816., 1816 November 1; engraving; 14 x 21.5 cm. (Box 2-161)
  Plan and Elevation of the Waterloo Bridge.
  Engravings; Waterloo Bridge (London, England)
- John Bacon Esq. F.A.S. London, Published by James Asperne, No. 32 Cornhill. 1st Fby. 1815., 1815 February 1; engraving; 16 x 12 cm. (Box 2-163)
- Entrance to Norbury Park., undated; engraving; 7 x 10.5 cm. (Box 2-165)
  Engravings; Norbury Park (England)
- Sir William Chambers. ...March 7, 1793. Published by Willm. Daniell No. 9 Cleveland Street, Fitzroy Square, London, Feby. 1st 1809., 1809 February 1; engraving; 23.5 x 15 cm. (Box 2-167)
- Charles Duke of Richmond, K.G. F.R.&A.S. Late a Vice President of the Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures and Commerce. Drawn and engraved by Wm. Evans, from an original picture by Romney in the possession of the present Duke of Richmond., undated; engraving; 17 x 10 cm. (Box 2-169)
  Portrait of Charles Lennox.
  Engravings; Richmond and Lennox, Charles Lennox, Duke of, 1735-1806
- Article on the Duke of Richmond's statue room, including a printed letter to the Duke of Richmond from W. Woollett., 1770 August 9; 1 page; 15 x 6.5 cm. (Box 2-170)
  Clippings; Woollett, William, 1735-1785; Richmond and Lennox, Charles Lennox, Duke of, 1735-1806
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1832 January 29; Barker, Edmund Henry, 1788-1839; 1 page; 20.5 x 21 cm. (Box 2-175)
  About his quotation from Baretti's Guide through the Royal Academy (London, 1781).
  Correspondence; Baretti, Giuseppe Marco Antonio, 1719-1789; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain)
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1828 September 5; Phillips, Molesworth, 1755-1832; 2 pages; 17.5 x 12 cm. (Box 2-179)
  About one of the paintings in Hogarth's Marriage a-la-mode: "The late Mr. Locke of Portman Square hinted to Hogarth that the third print...was not sufficiently understood. Mr. Hogarth seemed aware of the correctness of the suggestion...".
  Engravings; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Hogarth, William, 1697-1764
- Signed receipt from Joseph Wilton to Joseph Nollekens for five unspecified lots, 29 March 1776., 1776 March 29; Wilton, Joseph, 1722–1803; 1 page; 9 x 16 cm. (Box 2-180)
  Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Letter to George Colman., undated; Humphry, Ozias, 1742-1810; 2 pages; 23 x 18.5 cm. (Box 2-190)
  Asking for money for the sculptor Thomas Banks, on behalf of one "more ingenious and deserving".
  Correspondence; Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805; Colman, George